Unit 4, 78 Pampally Way Reservoir Hills, Durban, 4090 At this address

□ (+27) 67-076-0373 | Thandohimself@gmail.com | Athandohimself.github.io/ | □ Thandohimself

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

Software engineer with experience in multiple settings can design and develop programs using the latest and most appropriate technology. Coder who loves version control, OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience _____

immedia Umhlanga, KwaZulu-Natal

INTERN (HEAD START)

- May. 2019 December. 2019 • Migrated Java Features into Kotlin
- Implemented Fabrik POC'S
- Creation of Fabrik Tenants, e.g., Durban Girls' College, ASAIPA...to name a few
- Implemented UI & UX improvements across Codebase

immedia Umhlanga, KwaZulu-Natal

INTERN (HEAD START) MULTICHOICE (CAMPUS LIFE MOBILE APPLICATION)

- · Worked Closely with CMS team ensuring mobile application content was well aligned with Campus Life CMS
- Implemented UI improvements across mobile application

immedia Umhlanga, KwaZulu-Natal

INTERN (HEAD START) MULTICHOICE(SUPERSPORT MOBILE APPLICATION)

- Jan. 2019 May. 2019
- Migrated & Developed SuperSport mobile application into Xamarin • Consumed SuperSport Rest API and implemented Sign-in Feature
- Bug-fixes & Weekly Team Testing the SuperSport mobile application

immedia Umhlanga, KwaZulu-Natal

INTERN (WORK INTEGRATED LEARNING (WIL))

- MVVM design pattern
- · Consuming Rest APIs
- · C# language
- · Visual Studio IDE

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

- GIT flow
- Xamarin
- · Scrum and Agile methodology

Jan. 2019 - May. 2019

Jun. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Durban, 4031

Jan. 2018 - June. 2018

QvayaApp (Native Android/Java)

• Developed a Student Bus notification smartphone application which connects bus drivers and students.

- Implemented overall Android application logic and wrote PHP Scripts for community service, along with team engineers.
- Designed and implemented QvayaApp UI & UX.
- · Experience on making synchronous and asynchronous calls, consuming the web services of type RESTful, POST and parsing of data using the JSON. jsonschema2pojo
- Used Google Services for getting current user location after asking for permissions.
- Used open source libraries/dependencies
- Improve our code base through continuous refactoring
- Ensured the performance, quality, and responsiveness of application
- · Extensive work on implementing the best practices adhering to the android design principles
- · Meeting with the PO/Mentor to discuss requirement
- · Responsible for testing the application on various android devices and debugging the issues using Android Profiler and logcat.
- · Retrofit
- · Glide
- Timber
- · Butter Knife
- Picasso
- RxPermissions

511 Griffiths Mxenge Hwy, Umlazi,

THANDO LANGA · CV

School Registration System JAVA

Durban, KwaZulu-Natal

KEITSLEIGH SCHOOL POC Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Responsible for coding POJO Classes.
- · Involved in Functional Testing
- Implementing Business logic
- Generate Student reports using MySQL server as per required information.
- Ensure smooth functioning of the Management System.
- Writing UI / Business validations
- · Printing reports in PDF format
- Project was developed using NetBeans

Driver license barcode scanner POC

Durban, KwaZulu-Natal

Jan. 2017 - Mar. 2017

- App uses the Android device camera for scanning the Barcode on license disc/driver's. User would open app and point camera towards disk. was then able to read the Barcode. This side project is still at a early development stage
- · Involved in Functional Testing

Android/Java App

- · Contributed to the full development lifecycle of mobile phone applications from planning, Requirements gathering, development, testing, to maintenance/code enhancement.
- Focused on implementing rich user interface per UI/UX and Google's Material Design specifications.

Ingwe-Protections-service Business Profile

Durban, KwaZulu-Natal

Jan. 2017 - Jan. 2017

Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2016

INGWE-PROTECTIONS-SERVICE POC HTML

- Created a basic Business Profile for Ingwe-Protections-service in Html
- · Created A Navigation bar/Footer
- Used Photoshop for cleaning and cropping images/logos
- Text Information proved by Ingwe-Protections-service was styled using very basic CSS

HyperionDev Remote

STUDENT ONLINE BOOT CAMP PROGRAM

- · Completed Java course with the following
- · Java Syntax
- Java Comments
- · Java Variables
- Java For Loop
- · Java Method Overloading
- · Java Classes and Objects

Honors & Awards

BRETTONWOOD HIGH SCHOOL

Head Boys Award, Prefect Award Ceremony

Durban, KwaZulu-Natal

Presentation

Final Year Project Presentation

511 Griffiths Mxenge Hwy, Umlazi, Durban, 4031

Jun. 2018

QVAYA APP FILM DIRECTOR AND EDITOR

- · Directed and collaborated with team members in preparations for Qvaya App Film
- · Edited and released Film
- My team and I created a low production Short Film, mp4 link available upon request

Education

Mangosuthu University of Technology

511 Griffiths Mxenge Hwy, Umlazi, Durban, 4031

2016 - 2018

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY · Software Development Stream.

THANDO LANGA · CV